Guide to the Cased Image File 1840-ongoing PR 12
© 2011 New-York Historical Society
- Series I: Ambrotype, 1
  - John Gesner Conklin (Item 1-275)
    Accompanying note reads "John Gensner Conklin, a descendent of King William the 4th of the House of Orange, of the Netherlands--His ancestors were among the first settlers on Manhattan Island in the early 1620's and had a large farm (on of them was the fi
  - Mrs. James William Gowdey (Mary Elizabeth Concklin) [Weston] (Item 1-276)
    Female figure, seated with left arm on table, wearing horizontally striped dress, open finger gloves, black ribbon in hair.
  - Unidentified Gallagher Family Members (Item 1-277)
    Group portrait of male and female adult figures seated and young boy standing behind them with hands on their shoulders; older male is wearing large white tie and patterned vest; younger male is wearing plaid tie with white collar and dark jacket; female
    Accompanying note states "Relatives of James Wm. Gowdey but I do not know the names."
  - Unidentified Young Female Greenwood Family Member or Friend (Item 1-278)
    Little girl standing full length, left arm leaning on adjacent table and clasping hands; light hair in corkscrew curls, dark dress with stripes.
  - Unidentified Young Female Greenwood Family Member or Friend (Item 1-279)
    Young girl standing with left arm resting on table, half front view, wearing dark off-the-shoulder dress and hair neck-length in curls.
  - Isaac John Greenwood II (Item 1-280)
    Male figure, seated with right arm on back of chair, wearing white shirt, bow tie, long chain, ring, moustache.
  - Unidentified Young Male Greenwood Family Member or Friend (Item 1-281)
    Young boy, seated with left elbow on adjacent table, front view, wearing Buster Brown suit, striped bow tie, kerchief in breast pocket.
  - Mrs. Isaac John Greenwood II (Mary Agnes Rudd) [Young, J.H.], [1850s-1860s] (Item 1-282)
    Young girl, seated with right elbow on table, left hand on lap, wearing light colored polka dot off-the-shoulder dress, hair to just below ears and parted in middle.
    Sitter is daughter of Joseph Rudd of NY and wife of Isaac John Greenwood II.
  - Clarina Bartow Shumway (Mrs. Charles Stedman Hanks) (Item 1-283)
    Little girl, seated, front view, left hand on right, wearing short sleeved horizontally striped dress, hair parted in middle.
  - Mary Geery Hall (Item 1-284)
    Female figure, seated with left arm on table, right hand on left arm, wearing chain with locket around neck, bracelet on right wrist, ring, light dress with black lace and cloth trim.
    Original label in case identifies image as #14.
  - Sarah Cooper Hewitt [Anson, Rufus], 1859/06/18 (Item 1-285)
    Young girl, standing at side of table with left elbow leaning on table, white dress with sash at waist, front view, full length.
  - Unidentified Female Hincken Family Member or Friend (Item 1-286)
    Female figure, front view, seated, wearing ribboned bonnet, dark dress, white cuffs, hands on lap.
  - Unidentified Male Hincken Family Member or Friend (Item 1-287)
    Male figure, front view, seated, white shirt and high collar, clean-shaven, balding white hair.
  - Unidentified Young Male Hurlbutt Family Member, 1852/00/00 ca. (Item 1-288)
    Young boy seated with right arm resting on table, hair parted on side, wearing white collar, yellow buttons on blouse, bow tie, left arm on lap.
  - Unidentified Young Male Hurlbutt Family Member, 1852/00/00 ca. (Item 1-289)
    Young boy standing with left hand on back of chair, right hand on hip, hair parted on side, gold buttons on front of blouse, white collar, ring, striped bow tie, handkerchief in pocket.
  - Unidentified Young Female Hurlbutt Family Member (Item 1-290)
    Young girls seated with left arm on table, bracelets on both arms, rings on each hand, white dress, curls, earrings and brooch.
  - Rebecca Green Jewett (Mrs. Jesse Jewett) (Item 1-291)
    Female figure seated wearing dark bonnet with white trim, black gloves, white cuffs, bracelet.
    Sitter is wife of Jesse Jewett and grandmother of Hariett Rogers.
  - Cornelia Brinkman Kip (Item 1-292)
    Young girls seated, front view, wearing plaid dress with short sleeves, earrings, white lace collar, half length.
    Card catalog states that sitter married Wm. Henry Burr.
  - Polly Kellogg (Item 1-293)
    Female figure, front view, wearing white lace bonnet, white blouse, brooch, black dress (fades into background)
  - Silas Kellogg (Item 1-294)
    Male figure with white beard under chin, white hair, black coat and bow tie, white shirt, front view, elderly.
  - 2 Unidentified Young Male Livingston Family Members or Friends (Item 1-295)
    Two boys standing, full length, right hand of one on left shoulder of other, taller boy wearing plaid bow tie, bother wearing white shirts and collars.
  - Unidentified Female Livingston Family Member or Friend [Brady, Mathew B., 1823-1896], [ca1843-1869] (Item 1-296)
    Female figure, seated, front view, wearing white collar, braided bun in back of head, hands clasped on lap, velvet trim on black dress.
  - Mrs. Caroline E. Madden (Item 1-297)
    Female figure seated 3/4-length, holding accordion on lap, wearing necklace and brooch, left arm resting on table, bracelet on left wrist, black bow in hair.
    Sitter is daughter of Gerrit Smith of Rockland Co. and aunt of Donor.
  - John Stover McLean [Holmes, S. A. (Silas A.), 1819 or 20-1886], [1847-ca1858] (Item 1-298)
    Male figure, bust length, full face, dark hair, beard, wearing black bow tie and jacket, white shirt.
    Card catalog states that sitter was president of the Greenwich Savings Bank.
  - Schuyler Miller and Fannie Miller (Item 1-299)
    Boy and girl standing holding hands, both wearing pantaloons, boy wearing short checked dress, girl wearing plaid dress with black sleeves.
    Card catalog states that sitters are children of David and Jane Ann (Schuyler) Miller.
  - Unidentified Female MacMartin Family Member or Friend with Unidentified Young MacMartin Family Member or Friend [Keenan], [1853] (Item 1-300)
    Female figure with infant on her lap, front view, wearing bonnet with long ribbon under chin, right hand holding right hand of infant, infant wearing white gown with pink bows on sleeves.
  - Oxen Pulling Wagon in New Orleans, LA (Street Scene) [Broadbent, S.] (Item 1-301)
    Street scene, team of oxen harnessed to a conestoga type wagon, building behind them with sign reading "Sansom and Pittard", white building with shutters in the windows and a wrought iron railing on balcony, male figure leaning against wall in background.
  - Volunteer Fire Department with Hand Engine (17 Unidentified Male Firemen, William D. Lovelace, Unidentified Young Female Locke Family Member), before 1856/00/00 (Item 1-302)
    Group of thirteen male figures standing in foreground, five on one side of hand engine and eight on other side, young girl dressed in white standing on hand engine, male figures wearing red shirts, flat caps with gold medallions on front, male in foregrou
  - Catherine Stagg (Item 1-303)
    Female figure seated wearing checked dress, left arm leaning on table, wearing ring and brooch, hands on lap.
  - Unidentified Male Stagg Family Member or Friend (Item 1-304)
    Male figure seated with right arm resting on table, wearing plaid bow tie, dark jacket, necklace, moustache and goatee, ring, handkerchief in pocket with tassel?
  - Unidentified Female Stagg Family Member or Friend (Item 1-305)
    Female figure standing with left arm resting on railing, wearing feathered hat, white blouse, highly decorative dress/costume with pink sash, silver and gold lining, red boots.
  - Unidentified Young Male Stagg Family Member or Friend (Item 1-306)
    Young boy standing with left arm leaning on table which is covered in red cloth, wearing hat and green jacket and skirt with white shirt, full length, front view.
  - Unidentified Male Stagg Family Member or Friend (Item 1-307)
    Young male figure seated with hands on lap, wearing dark jacket and vest, dark thin bow tie, white shirt and collar, ring.
  - Ina Thursby (Item 1-308)
    Young girl, seated, full length, wearing red dress with floral design running horizontally at bottom of dress, coral colored necklace, bows on shoulders, right hand grasping arm of chair.
  - John Barnes Thursby (Item 1-309)
    Young male seated wearing soldiers uniform (probably of the Civil War period), front view, clean shaven, right elbow on table, yellow buttons up front of coat, wearing cap.
  - Unidentified Female [Schoonmaker] (Item 1-310)
    Female figure, front view, wearing white bonnet, light colored shawl, black dress, hands holding what appear to be knitting needles.
  - Mary Stiles Holly Windle (Item 1-311)
    Young girl, front view, seated, wearing a polka dot dress, short sleeves, white socks, black shoes.
  - Unidentified Female and Young Female Weymss Family Members, 1860/00/00-1861/00/00 ca. (Item 1-312)
    Adult female figure seated, front view, wearing dark dress with white collar and cuffs, brooch, long chain from neck, child standing on chair with left arm of adult around waist, wearing necklace and off the shoulder dress.
  - Anna Brookes Waller [Dean & Emerson], 1859/00/00-1860/00/00 ca. (Item 1-313)
    Female figure, front view, seated, long curls, hair parted in middle, polka dot dress, right elbow on table.
  - William G. Waller (Item 1-314)
    Male figure, front view, eyes wide open, bearded, wearing high white collar, large black bow tie, white shirt.
    Sitter is brother of Joseph F. Waller.
  - Unidentified Young Male (Item 1-315)
    Heavily hand-colored image of child wearing plaid off-the-shoulder dress with red bows at sleeves, belt with oval buckle, hair parted on side and extremely short, front view.
  - Unidentified Cahan Family Members [Opson, J.T.], 1850/00/00 ca. (Item 1-316)
    Seated male and female figures; female wearing earrings, long, chain front neck, white collar and cuffs, bracelet; male wearing white shirt, dark bow tie, pocket chain; both wearing rings and holding hands.
    Name and address of photographer stamped on mat; enclosed not identifies sitters as members of the Cahan family of Chicago.
  - Unidentified Male Crane Family Member or Friend (Item 1-317)
    Male figure seated with left arm resting on table, bearded, wearing white shirt and dark vest, jacket and bow tie.
  - Unidentified Female Crane Family Member or Friend (Item 1-318)
    Female figure, 3/4-length, seated, front view, wearing bonnet with ribbon and other ornaments, and gloves, as well as dark dress; right elbow resting on table and holding white handkerchief.
  - Unidentified Male Member of Rose Family, Protege of James Mathew Delano [Holmes, S. A. (Silas A.), 1819 or 20-1886], [1847-ca1858] (Item 1-319)
    Young boy, 3/4-length, front view, with left arm resting on table, standing, wearing white shirt and dark bow tie.
  - William Smith Valentine (Item 1-320)
    Bearded male figure, 3/4-length, front view, wearing white shirt and dark jacket with velvet lapel, with right arm resting on table out of frame.
    Sitter is father of Mrs. John Carthwaite Bierson and grandfather of donor.
  - Unidentified Female and Young Female Gilder Family Members or Friends [Fredericks? Research], [1843-1890] (Item 1-321)
    Female figure seated with infant on her lap, infant wearing white lace dress with pink belt, female figure wearing bonnet with black lace and pink ties at neck, white gown with patterned lining at sleeves.
  - Christina Arcularius Harper (Item 1-322)
    Young girl standing with left hand resting on table, wearing bracelets on both wrists, necklace and earrings, paisley dress.
    Card catalogue states that sitter is eldest sister of L.C. Harper.
  - Christina Arcularius Harper & Francis Perego Harper [Hunter], [1887] (Item 1-323)
    Figure in left frame of double case is of a young girl, front view, full length, seated wearing lace open finger gloves, necklace, backdrop of landscape; figure on right is of young boy wearing a plaid cape, left hand visible, curls, hat?, adult figure st
  - Abraham Lincoln (Item 1-324)
    Male figure, wearing beard, dark jacket, white shirt, bow tie, seated 3/4-front view, full length, right arm resting on table with hat and unidentified object, left arm resting on arm of chair.
  - 3 Unidentified Male Soldiers (Item 1-325)
    Three male figures in uniforms of Civil War soldiers, male on far left seated with cap tilted, moustache, holding sword across lap, center male standing with hands on shoulders of seated males, cap tilted, clean shaven, seated male to right clean shaven,
  - 2 Unidentified Young Females (Item 1-326)
    Two young girls, front view, girl on left standing, girl on right seated, both wearing matching off the shoulder white dresses with white socks and black boots, bows on dresses, hair parted in middle, holding hands.
  - William Remsen Sr. (or Jr.?) [Brady, Mathew B., 1823-1896], [ca1843-1869] (Item 1-327)
    Male figure, double ambrotype of same subject and pose, cemented back to back to be viewed on either side in case, fully-bearded, high white collar, white shirt, black bow tie, dark coat, gray vest.
  - John Barnes Thursby and Jane Bennett Thursby (2 Images in 1 Case), 1859/00/00 (Item 1-328)
    Male and female figures, male figure: front view, seated with right elbow on table, bearded, white shirt, black bow tie, chain on vest, black coat, gray trousers and vest; female figure: front view, seated with left arm on table, wearing earrings, brooch,
  - Unidentified Male [Jube, T.S.], [1850s-ca1858] (Item 1-329)
    Male figure seated, front view, wearing patterned vest with white shirt, black jacket and bow tie, bearded, moustache, hair parted on side, his right hand on lap, left arm resting on table, handkerchief in pocket, ring, brooch.
    Accompanying note states that Thomas S. Jube is first listed at this address as a clerk, later designation his business as "hardware" but not until 1868 does he list himself as a photographer as he changes his address to 220 Bowery.
  - Unidentified Female [Jube, T.S.], [1850s-ca1858] (Item 1-330)
    Female figure seated wearing blue dress with brooch, earrings, ring, black lining, white lace cuffs and collar, white blouse under dress, black lace gloves, ribbon at neck, ribbon in hair, her left arm resting on table.
  - Samuel Blackwell Waters, 1857/00/00 (Item 1-331)
    Male figure, front view, seated with legs crossed, moustache, dressed in military uniform with black crepe on right elbow, hat on table, left elbow on table.
    Sitter was member of 6th Company Seventh Regiment.
  - Unidentified Male and Unidentified Female (2 Images in 1 Case) [Guntekunst & Co.] (Item 1-332)
    L: Male figure, front view, seated with his left arm resting on table, wearing black jacket with dark plaid vest, black bow-tie, white shirt and high collar, pin on vest; R: Female figure seated wearing polka dot dress with black see-through shawl, white
  - Ray Feedson or Unidentified Male (Item 1-333)
    Male figure standing with right arm resting on pedestal, wearing dark tie and jacket, white shirt, beard under chin.
    Sitter's identification note is fairly undecipherable; sitter is identified as "Bill's grandfather".
  - Unidentified Young Female Greenwood Family Member or Friend (Item 1-334)
    Little girl seated in high chair, full figure, front view, with hands on lap, paisley shawl on chair, pink dress, black boots and horizontally striped stockings.
  - Clarkson Crolius Sr. (Item 1-335)
    Male figure, front view, with three large gilded buttons on coat and colonial type clothing.
    Mat stamp: "Dean Emerson-Patent Applied For, Worcester, Mass. No. 1"; Behind image case stamp: "Littlefield, Parsons & Co. Manufacturers of Daguerreotype Cases. L., P. & Co. are the sole proprietors and only legal manufacturers of Union Cases, with the em
  - Unidentified Male (Item 1-336)
    Male figure, front view, black coat with white shirt and polka dotted bow tie, 1/4 length, white hair.
  - Unidentified Male (Item 1-337)
    Male figure, front view, wearing black bow tie, white shirt, black jacket and pants, hair parted on side, seated with his right arm resting on table.
  - Unidentified Fireman [Kimball, J.A.], [1853-ca1860] (Item 1-338)
    Male figure seated wearing fireman's uniform with badge, fireman's hat with #14 and star on adjacent table, moustache, hair parted on side, front view, sitter looking off to right of camera, one gloved (?) hand resting on hat.
  - Unidentified Young Male Crane Family Member or Friend (Item 1-339)
    Young boy seated with left elbow resting on table and wearing buster brown collar, yellow buttons on front of blouse, and striped trousers.
  - Joseph Henry Edgerly (Item 1-340)
    Male figure, front view, seated next to table with top hat, left elbow on table, bearded, wearing white shirt and dark bow tie, as well as rings.
  - Maximillian Cabanas (Item 1-341)
    Military portrait of a male figure, about 14 or 16 years old, 3/4-length, wearing flat hat, white collar, large belt buckle, clean-shaven and holding gun under left arm.
    Enclosed notecard states that sitter was from Texas and enlisted in the confederate army; he was taken prisoner and died in a Northern Prison Camp at the age of 16; See also Roever, Mr. and Mrs. William B. (Agnes Cabanas).
  - Lathrop Colgate (Item 1-342)
    Child standing with left arm on back of chair, wearing checked dress, front view, full length, wearing white slip.
  - Mary Elizabeth Concklin (Item 1-343)
    Seated female with right elbow leaning on table, white collar and cuffs, and earrings.
    Case based on oil painting of Emily and Laura Calamady by Sir Thomas Lawrence (1769-1830) enclosed is a copy of the painting.
  - Unidentified Young Male Hurlbutt Family Member and Unidentified Female Hurlbutt Family Member, 1852/00/00 ca. (Item 1-344)
    Young boy standing and adult female seated, front view, boy wearing blouse buttoned down front, white collar, kerchief in pocket, arm resting on chair behind female, female wearing black hood and dress.
  - Frederick W. Budd (Item 1-345)
    Infant seated, front view, full length, wearing white gown
  - Helen Stagg (Mrs. William Miles) (Item 1-346)
    Female figure wearing off the shoulder patterned dress and hat with bow, front view.
  - Unidentified Female Harper Family Member (Item 1-347)
    Female figure, front view, hair parted in middle with headband, wearing plaid dress with white collar.
  - 195-199 Chatham Square and 9-17 East Broadway, New York, NY (Street Scene), 1842/00/00-1865/00/00 (Item 1-348)
    Early New York City street scene, in foreground is a curricular structure advertising caps and furs, pedestrians, several horse drawn carriages, buildings in background have signs reading "D. Balwin & Nesbitt, Furniture, etc."
  - Unidentified Female Hoffman Family Member (Item 1-349)
    Female figure, front view, wearing bonnet with white sash.
  - Louis Ramos and Sister (2 Images in 1 Case) [Cary], [1860s] (Item 1-350)
    Male figure seated with right arm resting on table, hair parted on side, wearing white collar, black bow tie, gray suit, watch chain on blouse, ring on left hand, female figure seated with left arm resting on table, wearing bracelets, rings, brooch, highl
    Sitters are brother and sister.
  - Thomas Shute and Mrs. Thomas Shute (Mary Ann Hayes) (Item 1-351)
    Male and female figures, front view, seated, left hand of male on lap of female under her left hand, male is bearded, wearing ascot, print vest, white shirt, female wearing bonnet with ribbon tied under chin.
    Sitters married 1844.
  - Maria Abernathy Burr (Item 1-352)
    Front view of female figure, hair parted in middle, checked dress, earrings, white collar and brooch.
    Enclosed note states that sitter is daughter of Melanthore Burr and Euphemia Cooper Burr.
  - Unidentified Male (Item 1-353)
    Male figure, front view, wearing dark jacket and vest, dark neckerchief, white shirt and white collar turned down, hair combed back, 1/3 length.
  - Emilie Frances Vaché and Isabella Vaché [Judson, A.], [1890s] (Item 1-354)
    Young girl holding infant in left arm and wearing plaid dress, short sleeves, necklace with cross, ring and earrings; infant wearing light dress with ruffled sleeves.
    Note from case states that sitters are children of John Vaché and Eliza Cox.
  - Emily Frances Collinson, 1856/05/00 (Item 1-355)
    Female figure, 3/4-length, seated wearing white collar and cuffs, brooch and chain on striped dress; backdrop depicts blue sky and vase of flowers.
  - Unidentified Male (Item 1-356)
    Male figure standing with his right hand resting on book on table, wearing black coat with dark vest and bow tie, white shirt, bearded, hair parted on side, front view, 3/4 length.
  - Unidentified Female Turner Family Member or Friend (Item 1-357)
    Female figure, half length, front view, wearing white veil on back of head, large sash in a bow under chin, horizontal striped blouse.
  - Old Nero (Dog), 1858/00/00 ca. (Item 1-358)
    Dog laying down with head up, on tile floor.
  - Unidentified Male [Cathan, L.], [1843-1850] (Item 1-359)
    Male figure, front view, seated, wearing black coat, black bow tie and vest, white shirt, bearded, moustache.
  - Unidentified Male with Dog [Cathan, L.], [1843-1850] (Item 1-360)
    Male figure seated holding musket across lap, powder horn hanging from shoulder, right hand holding dog still, log in background, patterned rug on floor, male is wearing large black hat and is looking off to his right, also wearing white shirt, bow tie, b
  - Mrs. Chas. S. Lewis (Elizabeth Harley), Matilda Anna Harley and Julianna Harley [Rehn] (Item 1-361)
    Three female figures, two seated wearing brooches, one standing center, standing female wearing earrings, checked dress, black shawl and gloves, bows on front of dress, female on right has hair parted in middle, earrings, white collar, holding throw?, sea
    Writing verso states that sitters are sisters.
  - Unidentified Male [Kerston], [1853] (Item 1-362)
    Male figure with his left arm resting table, wearing black jacket and vest, black bow tie, white shirt.
  - 9 Unidentified Young Females (Item 1-363)
    Nine young female figures seated wearing bonnets with long ties at neck, dresses of various patterns, including plaid, gloves, shawls, all front view.
    George T. Bagoe Collection.
  - Unidentified Male and Unidentified Female in Horse Drawn Carriage (Item 1-364)
    Male and Female figures seated in carriage, buildings in background, grass and path in foreground with horse, male wearing top hat, black jacket and tie, white shirt, bearded with sideburns, female wearing bonnet with plaid ties at neck, dark coat, horse
  - Unidentified Young Female [Bisbee] (Item 1-365)
    Young girl standing wearing off the shoulder patterned dress with socks and shoes, full length, dress is slightly large on girl, her right hand leaning on table, corkscrew curls in light colored hair, parted on side.
  - Unidentified Female (Item 1-366)
    Female figure, front view with her face in profile, wearing floor-length polka dot gown with white collar and cuffs, earrings, brooch, standing full length outside with fence in background, cobblestones and grass, her right hand holding back of chair.
  - Unidentified Female, Male and Young Van Kingbush Family Members (Item 1-367)
    Male figure seated wearing patterned vest and white shirt with high white collar, black jacket, checked bow-tie, his right hand on his knee holding what appears to be a cigar, holding young child on his lap with his left hand, child wearing white pantaloo
  - William Whitlock and B.McE. Whitlock (Item 1-368)
    Two you boys standing wearing matching outfits of large fur lined coats with hats and light colored pants.